[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 13]
In Chen Shoujie's mansion,
only a piece of fabric
from the Jinxiu Workshop was found.
But I need to check and see
in which year the pattern on it was made.
Not my concern.
Very well.
Jing Lin.
Yes, Grand Commander.
I will immediately take this mad woman
to the eighteenth floor of the prison of our Imperial Security Bureau.
I'm not asking you to take her back to the Imperial Security Bureau.
You take Miss Yun Que
to Shen's Mansion and let her stay there.
Miss Yun Que.
Please.
[Yan's Mansion]
Miss.
A maid from Shen's Mansion wants to see you.
Xiaohe.
Madam.
Please go back to the mansion quickly.
This morning, after Grand Commander left,
Yun Que became a totally different person.
If you don't discipline her right now, things will get out of hand.
Move this porcelain vase
there.
Wipe it clean.
The lantern in front...
Madam, look at her.
She has been bossing around
the people in our mansion.
She even mistook Grand Commander.
Grand Commander took pity on her
and kindly took her in.
But she...
She's acting like she's the mistress of the house.
We'd better use things
that match Grand Commander's Mansion.
You all should go out and see more of the world.
That way, when you go out and get cushions,
you'll know what the best option is.
Have you weeded the backyard?
Have you dusted the bookshelves
as Grand Commander asked you to?
If not, hurry up and do it.
I was instructing them to decorate the front hall.
Doesn't that count as important work?
Miss Yun Que.
Don't say that.
You misunderstood.
You can give the servants orders
and they should do their jobs well.
However,
we're paid by the Shen family.
We work for Grand Commander.
So first and foremost,
the tasks assigned by Grand Commander
should be our priorities.
It's understandable, right?
Then I'll discuss the decorations tomorrow.
Mr. Shen.
Arrange all the ledgers in the mansion
and get them to me.
I'd like to take a look at them.
I'm sorry, Miss.
The ledgers in the Shen family
can only be reviewed by the mistress of the house.
Madam.
Good morning.
Mr. Shen.
Why today...
Madam.
I forgot to greet you this morning.
Let me apologize to you.
Please punish me for it, Madam.
Punish you?
According to the rules of the Shen family,
all servants in Shen's Mansion
must greet the Madam in the morning and the evening.
The women in the mansion must also
bow and offer tea to the Madam.
Since the first day I came to the mansion,
I've kept this firmly in mind.
Shen's Mansion doesn't welcome those without good manners.
Today, I was being disrespectful to you.
Even if you are to
expel me from the mansion,
it will be entirely justified.
Alright, alright.
I know what you mean.
You just want me
to offer tea to Mrs. Shen, right?
I'll do it then.
Madam.
Please have some tea.
Now I've offered you the tea.
And you've let me know the rules.
Let's get things straight.
It was Grand Commander
who asked me to manage the household affairs.
Of course I should try my best.
Madam.
Are you going to
go against Grand Commander?
Miss Yun Que, you just said
you wanted to see the ledgers, right?
Yes.
Since you want to see them,
why don't you
manage all the ledgers for the next season?
This...
Madam.
You mean
you're going to let me handle all the ledgers?
I'm not good at
dealing with the accounts.
Miss Yun Que, since you want to help me with it,
that's perfect.
Madam.
Mr. Shen.
Please bring the ledgers and give them
to Miss Yun Que.
I've been on an errand recently.
Let Miss Yun Que
take care of all the affairs in the mansion.
Miss Yun Que.
Thank you.
Madam.
Please think carefully.
Sir made a mistake.
He must have been
bewitched by that girl.
She must have used some dirty tricks
to trick Sir into bringing her home.
Don't worry.
In his heart, you're always
his one and only wife.
Moreover, all of us
are on your side.
Butler Shen.
It really has nothing to do
with Miss Yun Que.
Madam.
I'm not stupid.
If you are not angry with her,
why are you
moving back to your parents' home?
Who said I'm moving back to my parents' home?
I've been busy investigating cases recently.
So I'm afraid I'll have to stay at the Ministry of Justice
and work late every day.
So I won't come back to sleep in the following days.
No need to worry about me.
Bye.
W-W-What should I do now?
Just say what you have to say.
Grand Commander.
In recent days when you've not been in your mansion,
Miss Yun Que
did things such as getting new porcelain plates,
buying new embroidered cloths and so on every day.
Uncle Zhong argued with her every day.
Today, he even gave me an order,
saying if I don't bring
you and your wife back,
he won't allow me to return to the mansion.
Since when
did Mr. Zhong start to like Yan Xing?
Grand Commander.
Can you just tell me the truth?
At first, I thought you were into
Miss Yun Que.
However, since
you brought her back to the mansion,
you haven't returned home at all.
I...
Whose side should I take?
Guard Jing, it seems you're not busy at all.
You even have time
to worry about my personal affairs.
I'm sorry.
Get up.
How are the security arrangements
for the upcoming days?
Grand Commander.
Everything is ready.
The security of the Palace Library
is now the responsibility
of Imperial Security Bureau.
The original guards
have been reassigned to support
the constables at the Hongwen Academy.
Jiang Langxing is there.
That's perfect.
Let's quickly finish talking and go home.
[Hongwen Academy]
Jiang Langxing.
Examinees are not allowed to talk to each other.
Commander Xu asked us to bring a message for you.
Listen.
The higher-ups
emphasized repeatedly that the exam is of great importance.
This time, the exam halls
must be so tightly watched that even a fly cannot get in
and that even one page of reference books cannot be brought in.
Understand?
Y-Y-You were speaking too fast.
I didn't follow.
Chuichui, Chuichui.
You can speak a little slower.
Besides,
Commander Xu also asked us
to go around and inspect
the security work
to see if there's anything wrong.
We need to inspect their work?
Ladies.
How about you come in with me to take a look?
There are several doors inside,
and we've set up checkpoints in the inner courtyard as well.
Chuichui.
Why don't you two go in first?
I'll wait here for Mojie
and see when he'll arrive.
Oh, right.
Your fifth brother also passed the preliminary exam.
Alright.
-Go.
-I’m going in then.
Jiang Guban.
Hurry up.
It's not easy to be a matchmaker.
Excuse me.
Could you
help me find someone?
Pan Chi.
[Ruan Jinping] [Jiang Han] [Ji Daozhang]
[Pan Chi] [Ji Jiashun] [Jiangxia County]
The person you're looking for
is indeed on the list of the final examinees.
But up until now,
he hasn't registered for the final exam yet.
[Hongwen Hall]
Pan.
Did you really give up?
Who said I gave up?
Pan.
It's really you.
You're here to take the exam.
That day,
after I sobered up,
I thought about what you said to me.
It's rare for the Hongwen Academy
to select candidates from everyone.
I'm so talented.
I must impress
those pedantic old scholars.
I'll let them see
what a truly exceptional piece of writing is.
Congratulations.
Then may you succeed in one go
and your name be on the list.
[Hongwen Hall]
Your name is Pan Chi.
The top folk detective's name is also Pan Chi.
You must be as excellent as him.
Today,
you look amazing.
Of course.
With just a bit of grooming,
I'll be so handsome and dashing
that I'll impress the people in Xiang'an.
Jokes aside,
you don't look well.
Have you been drinking again these past few days?
Recently,
I've been busy investigating cases and reviewing files.
But
I haven't found any clues.
[Hongwen Hall]
Is the case you're talking about
the one that involves
the flying moths?
You heard about it?
Of course.
People in the whole city all heard of it.
It's been spread around like some mystical tale.
But in my opinion,
you shouldn't just read the files.
You need to ask more people about it.
I've asked all the people around.
As for the people involved in the case,
one is dead,
and the other has gone mad.
So what?
People in our line of work
aren't afraid of corpses at all.
From the dead body,
we can get a lot of information.
Moreover,
what a madman says
might not all be nonsense.
[Lintai Pavilion]
[Please take your troops to me and cooperate with me.]
[Send troops to protect the Shen family after you enter the city.]
This handwriting
is my father's handwriting before he was injured.
When Lord Shen was young,
his brush strokes were as sharp as a sword,
powerful and magnificent.
But later on,
his strokes
got rid of the peculiarity
and became simple and smooth.
It took me a long time to practice
before I could have
such an identical handwriting.
[I followed you into the palace to work with you.]
So it is indeed forged.
If it was Dr. Yan who knew my father's handwriting
so well that framed him,
he would certainly not have used
the wrong strokes.
The forger
is someone else.
Pan.
Thank you.
Thanks to your reminder,
I seem to have got new ideas.
Me?
I didn't remind you of anything.
[Hongwen Hall]
Honey, I've been looking for you for long.
Shouldn't you be discussing cases at the Ministry of Justice?
How come you're here chatting with someone?
Grand Commander.
I'm here for work.
You should just take care of the affairs
in your Imperial Security Bureau.
What I do and where I go every day
is none of your business.
I can't interfere with the affairs of the Ministry of Justice.
But what if you don't
do your job well as the mistress of my house?
Our mansion is in a mess.
As the wife of the grand commander,
you should go back and take care of it.
Go home.
Do you expect that
you'll be the grand commander's wife just like Madam
and that you two can share a husband?
Let me tell you,
as long as I'm alive,
you'll never join the Shen family.
[Noble Aspiration] [Gentle and Humble]
That's not for you to decide.
Let me say it again,
Give me the ledgers.
Grand Commander, Madam.
[Noble Aspiration] [Gentle and Humble]
Sir.
You've brought Madam back.
As the old saying goes,
disagreements between a couple won't last long.
This is how you'll be a loving couple forever.
Mr. Shen.
I'm a bit hungry.
How about you go to the kitchen
and check on today's dishes?
Okay.
I'll go right away.
[Noble Aspiration] [Gentle and Humble]
Miss Yun Que.
Stop arguing with Butler Shen.
Don't worry.
The day Grand Commander and I got married,
I made an agreement with the grand commander
that we would get a divorce one day.
The ledgers
will be handled by you sooner or later.
Divorce?
The grand commander is such a wonderful man.
How come you don't cherish him?
Grand Commander is talented and handsome,
like a tall tree in the wind.
Whoever can't see this
is truly blind.
What a nice girl.
Unfortunately, her judgement of the grand commander is so wrong.
Why are you laughing?
Don't tell me
you think Grand Commander is ugly.
No, no, no,
Miss Yun Que.
You can eat wrong food,
but you can't say wrong words.
I think there's nothing more
for us to do here.
We'd better leave quickly.
Don't drag me.
Then walk yourself.
Go back to the mansion and stay there.
After all,
we...
I understand.
I'm not the person in your heart.
If outsiders find out,
it will only cause gossip.
After the case is solved,
I will come back.
I won't cause you any trouble.
[Hongwen Hall]
Her Majesty
has drawn the topic for the final exam.
We have been ordered to open it.
The topic is
"Appreciating the after-rain scenery of geese returning,
Viewing the grandeur of Xiang'an"
The form of writing is not limited,
but poetry and odes are preferred.
Take him away.
[Concluded]
[Test Paper of Pan Chi]
[Admission List]
Your Majesty.
We have been grading the papers for three days,
and have finalized the list of candidates
for admission to the Hongwen Academy.
We humbly request Your Majesty to review it.
The exam papers have been arranged according to their scores.
The one on the top
is the work by Cheng Bojian
who gets the highest score.
[Test Paper of Cheng Bojian]
[Test Paper of Pan Chi]
Pan Chi
gets the last place?
Yes.
Wan'er.
Read me the last-place examinee's
essay.
Tall pines grow at the foot of the mountain.
Short sprouts are born on the peak.
With stems just an inch thick,
they overshadow the pine branches hundred-foot tall.
I feel
the literary talent of the last-place examinee
is also quite remarkable.
Pan Chi
didn't lose because of his literary skills.
Instead,
his essay is a bit off-topic.
I'm afraid I don't quite
understand it.
Wan'er.
Please explain the essay to me.
The writer uses the tall pines
at the foot of Mount Yangui
to symbolize talented scholars from humble backgrounds.
The short sprouts on the mountaintop
represent the offspring of noble families.
Born in high positions,
these inch-tall sprouts
can overshadow the pines that are hundred-foot tall.
I think
the views of Mount Yangui
are described wonderfully by him.
Go on.
Laughing heartily to the sky,
I stride across the divine land.
[Hongwen Hall]
Though the noble deem themselves precious,
I see them as mere dust.
Though the humble consider themselves lowly,
who's to say they're not worth a thousand gold?
I shake my robes and gaze upon the mountains,
washing my feet in the long river.
I, Pan Chi, will not only take the exam
but also let people know
what dirty jobs you're doing.
I can tell your attention
is not focused on the chessboard.
Are you wondering why I still
approved the original list even though
I've told that
there's corruption in Hongwen Academy's
selection process?
I wanted to ask that question initially.
But I've just figured it out.
Although Pan Chi is talented,
he's too impulsive.
Therefore,
he's not suitable to be a government official.
This examination
is a pilot project.
The selection of talented scholars
has long been plagued by malpractices.
Many court officials
are involved in it,
making the problem
extremely difficult to deal with.
Though I want to deal with the problem,
I still need to see
when it's the right time to take action.
"I shake my robes and gaze upon the mountains,
washing my feet in the long river.''
This piece of writing is truly magnificent.
It uses scenery description to satirize the times,
suggesting that
some people are sidelining
scholars from humble backgrounds
in the name of fair selection
and thus solidifying the position of noble classes.
The essay is so penetrating.
Alright.
You've been praising your friend
for quite a while now.
Well, he did write exceptionally well.
Pan
not only
shares the name with the top folk detective.
It's very possible
he's the detective.
It's almost certainly true.
Miss Yan.
Commander Xu asked me to tell you
that the investigation you requested
into Chen Shoujie's background
has yielded some results.
Chen Shoujie indeed
participated in investigating the Chen Huo'e case,
and was even promoted because of it.
However, shortly after his promotion,
he went insane.
So before Mrs. Chen died,
he had already gone mad.
He must have some connection
with the fire moth case
that we haven't discovered yet.
Well.
I need to go to Chen's Mansion again.
Shen Du.
Are you alright?
Be careful!
Although the design of the hidden weapon is different from that day's,
the ways they're used
are very similar.
You're hurt.
It's nothing.
Just a minor wound.
Why did you come here alone?
I came to look for someone but I didn't find him.
You're bleeding so much.
How could you possibly be fine?
Are you worried about me?
I'm not worried about you at all.
You got hurt trying to save me.
I should at least take responsibility for it.
Father is really annoying.
The shop was properly closed.
Yet he still insisted me going there
to check if there's been any theft.
Want to run?
I advise you not to make another mistake.
I am a female official from the Ministry of Justice.
If you go to the government and report your crime voluntarily,
you might be given a lighter sentence for your theft.
But if you harm me,
that would be a serious offense.
You nosy woman.
Go to hell!
Help!
It's you.
Who's there?
Wait.
Wait a moment.
Just now,
those who were patrolling
are constables.
Why did we have to hide?
I
don't want to deal with government officials.
You avoid
dealing with government officials,
yet you're so skilled in martial arts.
I know your identity now.
You are
a chivalrous hero who likes to help others, right?
You're one of those who will put on a mask at night
and transform into a righteous warrior,
fighting for justice,
and doing good deeds anonymously.
I suppose so.
Wait a moment.
You can't leave.
You killed someone.
So what?
Are you going to turn me in to the authorities?
The person I killed was trying to kill you.
Is this how you treat
someone who saved your life?
According to the law of Cang State,
if someone tries to attack you without reason at night
and you resist the attacker and accidentally kill them,
you won't be punished.
However,
you can't just
go away like this.
What are you doing?
I'm releasing a water lantern for you.
When I was little,
my mother
often brought me here to release water lanterns.
Mother said
the water lanterns could float away with the current,
dispelling disasters and illnesses,
and could also
remove all the bad things
from our bodies.
Although you killed him to save me,
I still think
I should release a water lantern for you
to cleanse the karma of killing.
No need.
I don't believe in such things.
If you believe, it will work.
I didn't believe it when I was young either,
so I released them halfheartedly.
Later,
my mother's illness got worse and worse,
and she left me.
I often wonder
if back then,
I had sincerely
released every water lantern,
would the gods
have granted my wish
and let my mother stay with me forever.
Even if you release thousands or tens of thousands of water lanterns,
those who are meant to leave will still leave.
In this life,
they have already decided
to accompany us for only one journey.
It can't be changed.
Nothing can be changed.
Ghost Face.
Grand Commander.
The criminal hung himself in a deep alley.
We couldn't identify him.
He hung himself?
If he planned to kill himself once found,
they wouldn't let us
identify him.
You may go.
Yes.
Grand Commander.
Do you really not need me to call a doctor to check on you?
No need for ointment?
Mind your own business.
It's not necessary.
Who said it's not necessary?
Let me apply the ointment on you.
Do you have anything else to do later?
You seem to be in a hurry.
Surely you're not rushing off to rest, are you?
Of course not.
I was thinking...
If I finish treating your wounds
and it's not too late,
I could still go to the Ministry of Justice
to work on the case.
The work is so urgent
that you can't even rest at night?
Well, I just want to
solve the case sooner.
Staying up all night is no big deal.
But I'm injured.
Don't you think
you should stay and take care of me tonight?
I...
Never mind.
I don't need you to take care of me.
Go ahead with your work.
Fine, I'll stay.
Who said I was leaving?
You got hurt when you were saving me.
If I were to leave now,
even the gods would think
I have no conscience.
If the gods send
lightning to strike me down for it,
that would be so unfair to me.
♫The night is still young, and the moonlight reflects on the west window♫
♫There are stars in your eyes♫
♫When I touch you♫
♫My heart is like a flickering candlelight, shaking and swaying♫
♫The more I care, the deeper I hide♫
♫Leaves turn yellow and fall, and my thoughts run in thousands of lines♫
♫Time is like a poem, romantic and sorrowful♫
♫Two hearts♫
♫Collide between dawn and dusk♫
♫The embrace came as a surprise♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫I want to keep you by my side♫
♫Through the obstacle of wind and rain♫
♫I want to be your moonlight♫
I think you just pressed my wound.
♫Accompany you until every dawn♫
♫How I wish♫
♫I could just forget the passage of time like this♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫May we never forget each other♫
Don't be distracted.
♫There will always be a place for us to meet♫
Dress my wound carefully.
Okay, okay.
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫I want to keep you by my side♫
♫Through the obstacle of wind and rain♫
Maybe it's because just now
I didn't dress it well enough.
♫I want to be your moonlight♫
Now it's all good.
♫Accompany you until every dawn♫
♫How I wish♫
It's getting late.
You should rest early.
♫I could just forget the passage of time like this♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫May we never forget each other♫
♫There will always be a place for us to meet♫
♫I want to be with you forever♫
♫When our black hair turns grey♫
♫In this life♫
♫I'll only cherish you in my heart♫
My Lord.
My Lord, please don't kill me.
I've got the news
that the constables
have handled the case as a common one of thieves
fighting among themselves.
It's reported to the Ministry of Justice.
Useless!
Send more competent people to handle this.
If there's anything that goes wrong again,
You'll be the next to die.
Got it.
Thank you for not killing me, My Lord.
As for Lu Chuichui from the Ministry of Justice,
don't let anyone hurt her.
Understood.
You may leave now.
These ignorant fools.
A mere fire moth trick
can turn everything upside down.
It won't be long
before Cang State...
Get up first.
Go to the front hall and eat something.
When someone is injured,
they should eat more.
As you can see,
I'm severely injured now.
It's difficult for me to move.
Going to the front hall is too much trouble.
I just want to lie down.
Alright.
Then you rest well.
I'll
bring your breakfast here later.
Well.
Where's my wife?
Someone from Yan's Mansion came.
They invited Madam to their banquet.
She said that since are seriously injured,
you don't need to attend the banquet with her.
I...
She asked us to serve you well at mealtime.
You may go now.
Yes.
Grand Commander, I...
What is it?
I've found new information.
Han Shiyuan
is no ordinary person.
[Full of Nature Bestows]
Xing.
Shiyuan and I
will hold our wedding in the next month.
I'd like to use tea instead of wine
to toast to Sister Caiwei and Mr. Han.
May you be a happy couple forever.
I apologize for my impatience earlier
and any lack of proper etiquette.
Please forgive me.
Never mind.
Alright.
Take your seat.
Our Yan family this year
has one joyous event after another.
Mojie has been admitted to the Hongwen Academy.
Xing and Caiwei
found good husbands.
Xing.
Why did you come back frequently lately?
Are you and Grand Commander
not getting along?
No, no,
I'm doing well at Shen's Mansion.
It's just that a few days ago,
the cook
took a few days off to go home.
So the food there wasn't quite to my taste recently.
Then I came home for nice food.
Well, that's good then.
There are rumors out there,
saying that every time you come back here,
Grand Commander will come to take you away.
That's
a bit frightening.
But the last time you came home,
he didn't come to take you away.
And I was feeling uneasy about it.
Master, Madam.
The grand commander has come.
Grand Commander.
Grand Commander, please take the seat of honor.
Aren't you having difficulty moving?
It's my father-in-law's family dinner.
I couldn't miss it.
Yes, indeed, indeed.
Grand Commander.
Please, come in.